James Boland

Bachelor of Economics & Finance/Bachelor of Arts (Sociology) Graduate

Profile

University of Wollongong graduate with both an Economics & Sociology major across two degrees. A diverse employment background offers extensive experience in audio, client services, events, hotels, office administration, project management, financial modelling, and over five years of hospitality.

Employment History

Service Delivery Officer at Australian Taxation Office, Wollongong February 2020 — Present

- Handled inbound and outbound telephony enquiries, ensuring a positive client experience.
- Developed new procedures on a team to efficiently process new worktypes using a combination of online systems.
- Provided one on one and group support for new employees being trained in specific work types, relaying feedback to their team leaders.
- Reviewed ever-changing policies, procedures and legislation to ensure information relayed to clients was accurate and up to date.

Artist Support at Ableton Liveschool, Sydney

November 2019 — July 2020

- Assisted with studio and workshop setup for live artist demonstration.
- Dealt with the administration of new and potential students

Food & Beverage Attendant at Novotel Wollongong Northbeach, Wollongong

November 2015 — January 2021

- Gained extensive experience in customer service and dealt with international guests on a regular basis. Excelled in making guests feel welcome and getting to know them over their short term stay.
- Primarily stationed within the lobby bar. Have also regularly worked in different teams across the restaurant, room service and conferencing/events.
- Worked closely with the bar manager and operations manager in the decision making & planning for marketing or promotional events.

Event Crew/Guest Relations & Community Manager at The Yacht Week (Croatia), Split, Croatia

August 2018 — September 2018

 Aided in the operation of events and ensured that they ran smoothly throughout the week, whilst communicating efficiently with guests, skippers, and event management.

Details

Wollongong Australia 0415388267 james.boland94@hotmail.com

Links

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/james-boland-4079a717a

Skills

Effective Interpersonal Communication

Quick Learner

Adaptability

Emotional Intelligence

Creative Problem Solving

Teamwork

Technical Competency

Social Competency

Communication

Strategy and Leadership

Professional

- Filed event reports and dealt with the documentation of late arrivals.
- Ensured symmetrical, accurate information with guests in a personable manner.
- Acted as master of ceremonies at a few of the closing parties, giving the closing speech, thanking guests and announcing prize winners in front of 300+ people.

Data Analyst/Project Manager at Blockchain Partners, Wollongong

November 2017 — January 2018

- Used various economic and financial models to value digital assets in a financial market. Traded digital assets in real time.
- Lead and presented group projects to put forward R&D findings in valuation, risk management and international implications.

Education

Bachelor of Economics & Finance, University of Wollongong, Wollongong

February 2013 — November 2017

Full time. Economics major, Finance minor.

Bachelor of Arts (Sociology), University of Wollongong, Wollongong

February 2013 — November 2017

Full time.

Produce Music, Ableton Liveschool, Sydney

June 2019 — April 2020

Achievements

Solo Travel

April 2018 — September 2018

United States of America and Europe/Africa.

Surf Lifesaving Captain, Sydney

2012

St Ignatius College, Riverview NSW

Voluntary Fundraising

Voluntary fundraising for charities such as The Heart Foundation, Movember (ongoing), and Westmead Children's Hospital.

Music Project - EP album release

September 2020 — November 2020

Produced, organised, marketed and managed the release of a solo electronic music project ('bondla'). Organized online content working with graphic designers, videographers, photographers and audio engineers.

■ References

References available upon request